Guide to the Stan Steiner Papers, ca. 1940-1987 M0700
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series III. Manuscripts by Steiner
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XXII. The Lone Wolf: Carlos Montezuma n.d. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: XXIII. I suppose I am a heathen n.d. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    TMs, 18 pp.
  - The Notebooks of Wa Wa Chaw [The Spirit Woman]: Epilogue: Death is a impolite superstition n.d. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Notes on the Cosmic Cowboys. Across the Board.--Vol. 21, no. 2 1984 Feb. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Of Blood and Death / The Region of the Damned -- Notes: Texas Council of Churches & Valle n.d. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Old Poems [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Old Poems [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Old Poems [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - On the Border [Gallup, NM] [1 of 2] c. 1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    7 TMs
  - On the Border [Gallup, NM] [2 of 2] c. 1974 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - On Going West n.d. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - ...On Hungary, Eastern Europe (clippings and drafts) n.d. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    "Bridges over the Danube: book proposal," TMs, 28 pp.; "Man can make himself free: a talk with some Hungarian writers," TMs, 14 pp.; "In opposition to ourselves: the official position," TMs, 18 pp.
  - On writing about ranchers n.d. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - On writing about ranchers. The Roundup.--Vol. 27, no. 5 1979 May (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - On writing about ranchers. The Roundup. n.d. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - One hundred year old Cowboy n.d. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Overthrow the Song of Songs (Woman, man and the wiles of automation) 1955 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    TMs, 58 pp.
  - El Patrio: The untold story of Joaquin Murieta: notes [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - El Patrio: The untold story of Joaquin Murieta: notes [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - El Patrio: The untold story of Joaquin Murieta: notes [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Poems [1 of 8] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Poems [2 of 8] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Poems [3 of 8] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Poems [4 of 8] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Poems [5 of 8] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Poems [6 of 8] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Poems [7 of 8] n.d. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Poems [8 of 8] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Poetica Scientificus [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Poetica Scientificus [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Poetica Scientificus [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Pornography for Kids: What were Jack and Jill really up to up that hill? n.d. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Promised Land: The Western History of the American West: outline n.d. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - [The Promised Land]: The New History of the American West: outline n.d. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Punny Man n.d. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    TMs (carbons), 23 pp.
  - Racism and Immigration n.d. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: prologue and contents n.d. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: The Book notes [1 of 5] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: The Book notes [2 of 5] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: The Book notes [3 of 5] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: The Book notes [4 of 5] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: The Book notes [5 of 5] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: prologue and epilogue n.d. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: outline of chapters n.d. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: dedication to Boyd [Charter] n.d. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Allen, Gerald n.d. (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Attebury, Lou n.d. (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Barker, Elliot n.d. (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Barker, Omar n.d. (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Bundy, Rex n.d. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Charter, Boyd & Anne n.d. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Chrisman n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Hill, Janaloo n.d. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Jonasson, Stan n.d. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Lumpkin, Bill n.d. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: McRae, Wallace - poems 1978 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: McRae, Wallace (Wally) - Rocker Six Ranch n.d. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Myers, Rex C. {Montana Historical Society] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Pettit, Ruth and Tug n.d. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Shiveley, Frank y Marian n.d. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Sitz, Glen n.d. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Skinner Ranch n.d. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Sprague's Ranch n.d. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Stephenson, Billy n.d. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations: Vincent, Jenny Ferry 1977 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [1 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [2 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 18)
    TMs, pp. 51 -99
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [3 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 19)
    TMs, pp. 100 -152
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [4 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 20)
    TMs, pp. 153 -200
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [5 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 21)
    TMs, pp. 201 -248
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [6 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 22)
    TMs, pp. 249 -299
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [7 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 23)
    TMs, pp. 300 -352
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [8 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 24)
    TMs, pp. 353 -404
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [9 of 15] n.d. (Box 20, Folder 25)
    TMs, pp. 405 -449
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [10 of 15] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    TMs, pp. 450 -495
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [11 of 15] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    TMs, pp. 496 -552
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [12 of 15] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    TMs, pp. 553 -597
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [13 of 15] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    TMs, pp. 598 -649
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [14 of 15] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    TMs, pp. 550 -698
  - The Ranchers: A Book of Generations [15 of 15] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    TMs, pp. 699 -743
  - The Ranchers: Nebraska TV Film [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    includes: "Meanwhile back at the Ranch: Comments by Stan Steiner," TMs, 7 pp.
  - The Ranchers: Nebraska TV Film [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Refuge under a healing sky. New York Times 1986 July 27 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Remembering an earlier New Mexico. New Mexico Magazine.--Vol. 62, no. 6 1984 June (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Requiem for Santa Fe: notes 1983 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Requiem for Santa Fe: notes y etc. n.d. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Requiem for Santa Fe: outlines n.d. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Requiem for Santa Fe: outlines n.d. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    "The end of the Santa Fe trail," TMs, 14 pp.
  - Requiem for Santa Fe: correspondence n.d. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - The Reunion: notes 1981 -1982 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Review of Dary, David. "Cowboy Culture" 1982 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Review of Martin, Russell. "Cowboy: The Enduring Myth of the Wild West" 1983 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Riders of the Range. Natural History.--Vol. 93, no. 2 1984 Feb. (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Santa Fe Land Rush. Forbes 400 1985 Oct. 28 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Les Sauvages of Paris n.d. (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - The Secrets n.d. (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - The Sioux Today n.d. (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - The Snow Children [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - The Snow Children [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    "The Innocent Sinners"
  - Society and Solitude: Gunmen and Lawmen n.d. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Society and Solitude n.d. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - South Dakota Lawyer: Mitchell, South Dakota n.d. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Exploration in the Southwest n.d. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Exploration in the Southwest: for Insight Guide: Southwest n.d. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Spirit Woman [1 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - The Spirit Woman [2 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    TMs, pp. 1 -51
  - The Spirit Woman [3 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    TMs, pp. 52 -75
  - The Spirit Woman [4 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 10)
    TMs, pp. 76 -114
  - The Spirit Woman [5 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    TMs, pp. 115 -147
  - The Spirit Woman [6 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 12)
    TMs, pp. 148 -177
  - The Spirit Woman [7 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 13)
    TMs, pp. 178 -208
  - The Spirit Woman [8 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 14)
    TMs, pp. 209 -227
  - The Spirit Woman [9 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    TMs, pp. 228 -262
  - The Spirit Woman [10 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 16)
    TMs, pp. 263 -281
  - The Spirit Woman [11 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 17)
    TMs, pp. 282 -307
  - The Spirit Woman [12 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 18)
    TMs, pp. 308 -345
  - The Spirit Woman [13 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 19)
    TMs, pp. 346 -396
  - The Spirit Woman [14 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 20)
    TMs, pp. 397 -429
  - The Spirit Woman [15 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 21)
    TMs, pp. 430 -439
  - The Spirit Woman [16 of 22] n.d. (Box 22, Folder 22)
    TMs, pp. 440 -476
  - The Spirit Woman [17 of 22] n.d. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    TMs, pp. 477 -492
  - The Spirit Woman [18 of 22] n.d. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    TMs, pp. 493 -517
  - The Spirit Woman [19 of 22] n.d. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    TMs, pp. 518 -544
  - The Spirit Woman [20 of 22] n.d. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    TMs, pp. 545 -573
  - The Spirit Woman [21 of 22] n.d. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    TMs, pp. 574 -612
  - The Spirit Woman [22 of 22] n.d. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    TMs, pp. 613 -645
  - The Spirit Woman n.d. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - The Spirit Woman: publicity n.d. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - The Spirit Woman: Wa Wa mementos and miscellany n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - State of New Mexico: Anniversary issue 1986 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - The Suburban Nests n.d. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - The Suburban Nests n.d. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - The Superb Masculinity of the West: outlines n.d. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - The Suffering of All, the Joy of All. Nuestro Magazine 1976 -1977 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Talk with Hungarian writers n.d. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - The Tiguas: page proofs n.d. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - The Tiguas: "In the gentle wind..." n.d. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - The Tiguas: The promised land and front flap draft n.d. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - The Tiguas: El Barrio de los Indios n.d. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - The Tiguas: Journey of Death n.d. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - The Tiguas: The Lost Tribe n.d. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - The Tiguas: The Ghostly Ruins n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - The Tiguas: Who was the First Texan? n.d. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - The Tiguas: The Warrior Chiefs of the Peaceful People n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - The Tiguas: Medicine of the Sun n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - The Tiguas: The Talking Drum n.d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - The Tiguas: The Scalping Song n.d. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - The Tiguas: Mystery of the Hueco Caves n.d. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - The Tiguas: The Hunt of the Extinct Deer n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - The Tiguas: The Garden of Eden n.d. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - The Tiguas n.d. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - The Tiguas [1 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    "I. Dancing on the Highway," TMs, 12 pp.
  - The Tiguas [2 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    "The Secrets," TMs, 8 pp.
  - The Tiguas [3 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 13)
    "The Ghostly Ruins of Gran Quivera," TMs, 12 pp.
  - The Tiguas [4 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 14)
    "El Barrio de los Indios," TMs, 10 pp.
  - The Tiguas [5 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 15)
    "The Journey of Death," TMs, 11 pp.
  - The Tiguas [6 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 16)
    "The Lost Tribe," TMs, 9 pp.
  - The Tiguas [7 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 17)
    "The Land of the Tiguas," TMs, 10 pp.
  - The Tiguas [8 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 18)
    "The Warrior Chiefs of the Peaceful People," TMs, 12 pp.
  - The Tiguas [9 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 19)
    "Medicine of the Sun," TMs, 9 pp.
  - The Tiguas [10 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 20)
    "The Talking Drum," TMs, 14 pp.
  - The Tiguas [11 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 21)
    "The Scalping Song," TMs, 6 pp.
  - The Tiguas [12 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 22)
    "Mystery of the Hueco Caves," TMs, 14 pp.
  - The Tiguas [13 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 23)
    "The Hunt for the Extinct Deer," TMs, 13 pp.
  - The Tiguas [14 of 14] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 24)
    "The Promised Land," TMs, 11 pp.
  - Tom Bell, High Country News n.d. (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - The Ugly Art 1961 -1963 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - The Unfrocked Priests n.d. (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - The Unfrocked Priests: notes n.d. (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [1 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [2 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [3 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [4 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [5 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [6 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [7 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [8 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [9 of 9] n.d. (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [1 of 5] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [2 of 5] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [3 of 5] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [4 of 5] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - The Vanishing White Man: notes [5 of 5] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - The Vanishing White Man: outlines [1 of 2] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - The Vanishing White Man: outlines [2 of 2] n.d. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - The Vanishing White Man: production n.d. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [1 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    TMs, pp. 1 -47
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [2 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    TMs, pp. 48 -99
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [3 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    TMs, pp. 100 -149
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [4 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    TMs, pp. 150 -199
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [5 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    TMs, pp. 200 -248
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [6 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [7 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    TMs, pp. 300 -349
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [8 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 16)
    TMs, pp. 350 -397
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [9 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 17)
    TMs, pp. 398 -449
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [10 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 25, Folder 18)
    TMs, pp. 450 -499
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [11 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    TMs, pp. 500 -549
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [12 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    TMs, pp. 550 -594
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [13 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    TMs, pp. 594 -649
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [14 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    TMs, pp. 650 -716
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [15 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    TMs, pp. 717 -799
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [16 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    TMs, pp. 800 -848
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [17 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    TMs, pp. 849 -899
  - The Vanishing White Man: Xerox corrected manuscript [18 of 18] 1976 Feb. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    TMs, pp. 900 -922
  - The Vanishing White Man: University of Oklahoma 1986 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - A View from the West n.d. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - A View from the West n.d. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - A View from the West: A View from the West [1 of 4] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - A View from the West: The Suburban Cowboys [2 of 4] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - A View from the West: Shangri-La is crowded [3 of 4] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - A View from the West: Mr. Jordan went to Washington [4 of 4] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Craig Vincent: The Last of a Breed n.d. (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - The Waning of the West. Natural History Special Supplement 1975 June -July (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - George Washington: galleys 1970 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    TMs, 51 pp.
  - George Washington: On the Frontier of Freedom c. 1967 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    TMs, 50 pp.
  - Washington Post - Vine's book [review of Deloria, Vine. "Behind the Trail of Broken Promises"] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - The Water is so clear, a blind man could see: television script [1 of 2] 1970 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    3 TMs
  - The Water is so clear, a blind man could see: television script [2 of 2] 1970 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Weep / to see if your eyes are clear [poem] n.d. (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - The Western History of the American West: A Series: prospectus n.d. (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - The Western History of the American West: A Series n.d. (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - The Western History of the American West: proposal n.d. (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - The Western History of the American West: A Series: prospectus n.d. (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Western writings: Dark and Dashing Horsemen n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Western writings: The Man who invented OPEC n.d. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Western writings: Nations or Tribes n.d. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Western writings: A View from the West n.d. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Western writings: A Western History of the American West: a series n.d. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Western writings: On writing about Ranchers n.d. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - The Westerners: Facing an era calling for new heroes n.d. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - The Westerners: Facing an era calling for new heroes n.d. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies: notes n.d. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies: proposal c. 1986 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [1 of 10] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    "The Ghost of Sonora: a book proposal," TMs, 32 pp.
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [2 of 10] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 12)
    "On the trail of Joaquin Murieta, or, The Writing of Unwritten history," TMs, 32 pp.
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [3 of 10] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 13)
    "On the trail of Joaquin Murieta, or, The Writing of Unwritten history," TMs, 14 pp.
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [4 of 10] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    "The Ghost of Sonora: a book proposal," TMs, 38 pp.
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [5 of 10] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 15)
    "And when the owl hoots: a book proposal," TMs, 10 pp.
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [6 of 10] 1976 Aug. 30 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    "When the owl hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens: a proposal for a book," TMs, 11 pp.
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [7 of 10] 1980 Oct. (Box 27, Folder 17)
    "On the trail of Joaquin Murieta, or, The Writing of Unwritten history," TMs, 22 pp.
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [8 of 10] 1981 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    "On the trail of Joaquin Murieta" The American West.--Vol. 18, no. 1 (1981 Jan. -Feb.): 54 -57
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens [9 of 10] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - When the Owl Hoots, the Indian Dies this may not be true but it happens: correspondence [10 of 10] 1980 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - A Word has Power: Italia n.d. (Box 27, Folder 21)
    TMs, 11 pp.; "Going West," TMs, 13 pp.
  - The Yahoos: Playboy series [1 of 5] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 22)
    "The Yahoos," TMs, 11 pp.
  - The Yahoos: Playboy series [2 of 5] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 23)
    "The Politicians," TMs, 14 pp.
  - The Yahoos: Playboy series [3 of 5] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 24)
    "The Conspirator Catchers," TMs, 12 pp.
  - The Yahoos: Playboy series [4 of 5] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - The Yahoos: Playboy series [5 of 5] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 26)
    Newberry, Mike. "The role of the CIA and FBI in Rightist Politics: The James Bonds of Extremism," TMs, 31 pp.
  - The Year of the Chicano n.d. (Box 27, Folder 27)
    TMs, 31 pp.; TLS
  - The Year of the Chicano n.d. (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - The Year of the Chicano n.d. (Box 27, Folder 29)
    TMs, 33 pp.; TMs, 14 pp.
  - The Year of the Thinking People: The New Indian n.d. (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - XVII ["Hand by hand, rock by rock..."] n.d. (Box 27, Folder 31)
    TMs (3 copies), 10 pp.
  - XVIII ["Like the masques of clown dancers..."] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    TMs (3 copies), 15 pp.
  - XIX ["How do you rip up a gas station?"] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - XX ["It was quiet..."] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - XXI ["Up on the highway, in the twilight..."] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - XXII ["The wife of Old Singer..."] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - XXIII ["I have bought the truck"] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - XXIV ["Dr. Ruhrbock decided to die..."] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - XXV ["O Sun of my father..."] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified manuscript [1 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified manuscript [2 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified manuscript [3 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified manuscript [4 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified manuscript [5 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified manuscript [6 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified manuscript [7 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified manuscript [8 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified manuscript [9 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified manuscript [10 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Unidentified manuscript [11 of 11] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified miscellany n.d. (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified notes n.d. (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Untitled ["City in the sky"] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Untitled ["In the twilight of the twenty-third day..."] [1 of 3] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Untitled ["Miss Christina Suna, Jeanette Sweet..."] [2 of 3] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Untitled [3 of 3] n.d. (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous notes n.d. (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Newberry, Mike. "Musical History in Folksongs" n.d. (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Coles, Robert, Frank Waters, Stan Steiner, & Charles Keil. "Embracing Queequeg: Cultural Estrangement and Cross-Cultural Affiliation in the Writing of Ethnic Studies" n.d. (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes [1 of 10] n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes [2 of 10] n.d. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts and notes [3 of 10] n.d. (Box 29, Folder 3)